<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-19T19:02:03-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Florida Poly Student Government</title><subtitle>Welcome to the Florida Poly Student Government page!  Here you can find all of our official documents  including statutes, meeting minutes, and more!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Legislative Committees</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/LegislativeCommittees/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Legislative Committees" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/legislative_committees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/LegislativeCommittees/">&lt;p&gt;Florida Poly’s Student Government Association currently has four legistaltive committees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;legislative-executive-board&quot;&gt;Legislative Executive Board&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Legislative Executive Board (LEB) deals with overseeing general operations of the Senate and creating policy. A major role of the LEB is to conduct Senator accountability reports, discuss weekly committee updates, and ensure that the Senate is operating effectively. The LEB is comprised of five voting members: Senate President, Senate President Pro Tempore, Audit and Budget Committee Chair, Student Organizations Committee Chair, and Information and Communications Committee Chair.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:senate@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Legislative Executive Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;audit-and-budget-committee&quot;&gt;Audit and Budget Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Audit and Budget Committee (ABC) deals with Student Government’s funding. A major role of the ABC is to help Registered Student Organizations (RSO) receive funding by submitting a budget proposal and going through revisions which will then be passed on to Senate to see if there are any more revisions needed. The ABC is committed to helping students and RSOs receive funding through certain line items in the SGA Budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ABC@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Audit and Budget Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;student-organizations-committee&quot;&gt;Student Organizations Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Organizations Committee (SOC) deals with student organizations and clubs. A major role of the SOC is to approve and manage Registered Student Organizations. Students may submit paperwork to apply for a new organization at any time, and the SOC will work with the students through the process. The SOC is here for the students and to help create a better, more active campus life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SOC@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Student Organizations Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;information-and-communications-committee&quot;&gt;Information and Communications Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Information and Communications Committee (ICC) deals with SGA and Legislative Branch communication. A major role of the ICC is to help keep students and other SGA members informed. The ICC is committed to keeping SGA and students informed throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ICC@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Information and Communication Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="AboutSGA" /><summary type="html">Florida Poly’s Student Government Association currently has four legistaltive committees.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SGA Constitution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AboutConstitution/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SGA Constitution" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/about_constitution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AboutConstitution/">&lt;p&gt;The Florida Polytechnic University Student Constitution, enacted in February 2015, is a dynamic document that establishes the Student Government Association, its mission, powers, and duties. With the signing of the Constitution, the SGA is formally operated by the students and for the students, a highly visible testament to democracy at the university level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;statutes&quot;&gt;Statutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Statutes/TitleI/&quot;&gt;Title I - Introduction to SGA Statutes&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Statutes/TitleII/&quot;&gt;Title II - Officer Procedures&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Statutes/TitleIII/&quot;&gt;Title III - The Executive Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Statutes/TitleIV/&quot;&gt;Title IV - The Legislative Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Statutes/TitleV/&quot;&gt;Title V - The Judicial Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/Statutes/TitleVI/&quot;&gt;Title VI - Elections&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="AboutSGA" /><summary type="html">The Florida Polytechnic University Student Constitution, enacted in February 2015, is a dynamic document that establishes the Student Government Association, its mission, powers, and duties. With the signing of the Constitution, the SGA is formally operated by the students and for the students, a highly visible testament to democracy at the university level.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SGA Branches</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Branches/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SGA Branches" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/branches</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Branches/">&lt;p&gt;The Student Government Association is composed of an Executive, Legislative, and Judicial branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;executive-branch&quot;&gt;Executive Branch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Executive Branch includes the Student Body President, Vice President, Treasurer, Secretary, and an Executive Cabinet. The Cabinet includes various Executive Committees as appointed by the Student Body President. They are the students’ voice and liaison between the students and the administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sgavicepresident@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Contact the Executive Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;legislative-branch&quot;&gt;Legislative Branch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Legislative Branch is comprised of senators represented by class years, degree programs, and on- and off-campus students. The Senate enacts statutes, allocates funds and oversees campus organizations. The Legislative Branch will grow as the University grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/LegislativeCommittees/&quot;&gt;View All Committees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;judicial-branch&quot;&gt;Judicial Branch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Judicial Branch is the Supreme Court, comprised of a Chief Justice and six Associate Justices. The seven Justices are appointed by the Student Body President and confirmed by the Senate. The Supreme Court hears student concerns, helps conduct all SGA elections and holds trials for officials who breach the SGA Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sgajudicial@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Contact the Judicial Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="AboutSGA" /><summary type="html">The Student Government Association is composed of an Executive, Legislative, and Judicial branch.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Constitution of the Student Body of Florida Polytechnic University</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Constitution/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Constitution of the Student Body of Florida Polytechnic University" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/constitution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Constitution/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ConstitutionHeader.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-constitution-of-the-student-body-of-florida-polytechnic-university&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;The Constitution of the Student Body of Florida Polytechnic University&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Adopted by the Florida Polytechnic University Student Body on &lt;i&gt;February 4th of 2015&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We, the Student Body of the Florida Polytechnic University:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Represent and defend the rights and interests of our students to the University, local community, and government&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide a forum for the expressions of student views and interests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Promote the academic freedom and responsibility and high standards of education&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide services and organize events for the benefit of students&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognize and understand our responsibilities to the University, local community, and humanity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do hereby establish this Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-i-declaration-of-rights-and-responsibilities&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article I: DECLARATION OF RIGHTS AND RESPONSIBILITIES&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-political-power&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Political power.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All political power granted by authorities authorized under the Constitution of the State of Florida, laws, and regulations of the State of Florida is inherent in the Student Body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-basic-rights&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Basic rights.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every student is guaranteed certain rights under the constitutions and laws of the United States and State of Florida. Student government recognizes these rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally students are guaranteed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The right to vote in student government elections.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The right to submit initiatives and referendums for ratification by the electorate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The right to recall and remove elected officials from office, through process Stated in &lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article VII, Section 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The right to address student government officials at regularly scheduled times and places.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-honor-code&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Honor Code.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Students are bound by the Honor Code and shall be held accountable to it. The Honor Code states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;“We, the members of the Florida Polytechnic University community, pledge to hold ourselves and our peers to the highest standards of honesty and integrity.”&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-discrimination-prohibited&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4. Discrimination Prohibited.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Government Association (SGA) and any organization that receives SGA funding shall not discriminate on the basis of race, creed, color, religion, age, disability, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity and expression, marital status, national origin, political opinions or affiliations, veteran status, legal status, or any other classification as provided by law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-ii-general-provisions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article II: GENERAL PROVISIONS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-student-body&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Student Body.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body shall be held to SGA laws put forth, as well as entitled to all privileges and immunities of students provided for, in this: “The Constitution of the Student Body of Florida Polytechnic University”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-student-government&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Student government.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All student Government officials shall be full-time students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-student-government-officials&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Student Government Officials.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Government shall be divided into a Legislative, an Executive, and a Judicial branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-branches-of-government&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4. Branches of government.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Government shall be divided into a Legislative, an Executive, and a Judicial branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;A. Exercise of Powers.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;No person belonging to one (1) branch shall exercise any powers appertaining to either of the other branches unless expressly provided by the Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;B. Exclusionary of Powers.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;The Senate may provide by Code of Conduct for Student Government offices considered exclusionary, but the following positions shall always be exclusionary: Student Body President, Student Body Vice President, Student Body Treasurer, Student Body Chief of Staff, Supervisor of Elections (or election committee), Heads of Cabinet or Agency Heads, and Cabinet Directors for the Executive Branch.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;C. Offices Explicitly Non-exclusionary.&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Nothing in this Constitution shall be construed to prohibit any student from holding an exclusionary office and simultaneously holding as a member of the Constitution Revision Commission, a member of an independent body having only advisory powers created by Student Body Statutes, or a member of a committee or commission created by the Student Body President.&lt;/p&gt;&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-iii-the-legislature&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article III: THE LEGISLATURE&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-legislative-authority&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Legislative Authority&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legislative authority of the Student Body shall be vested in the Student Senate herein after referred to as “The Senate”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-composition&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Composition&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;A. Division of Representation&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;
			&lt;ul style=&quot;PADDING-LEFT: 75px&quot;&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;The Senate will be composed of representatives from each of the Colleges of the University. Graduate and Undecided/Non-Degree Seeking Students shall each be considered a separate college for the purpose of composing the Senate. Seats will also be allocated for the Freshman, Sophomore, Junior, and Senior class along with a seat for on-campus and off-campus students. The total number of Senate seats will be ten (10) plus one (1) seat for every 240 students with a maximum number of thirty (30) senators. Every College will have at least one (1) representative. The apportionment of the seats will be set according to the percentages of the total number of students enrolled at each of the respective Colleges as outlined within the Constitution or Statutes.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;If passed, this amendment will go into effect for the 2020 spring general election.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ul&gt;
	&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;B. Structure of Senate&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;There shall be a:&lt;/p&gt;
			&lt;ul style=&quot;PADDING-LEFT: 75px&quot;&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Senate President, elected by The Senate to be the Speaker of the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Senate President Pro Tempore, nominated by the Senate President and approved by The Senate to act as speaker in absence of the President.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;A number of officers elected or appointed as stated in the Senate Rules and Procedures as written and designed by The Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ul&gt;
		&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-senate-session&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Senate Session&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous Senate will be dissolved once the President of the new Senate is confirmed at the first official Senate meeting after the Fall semester election, in which both the previous Senate and the new Senate are present. At such time, the new Senate session will begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-election-of-the-senate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4. Election of the Senate&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate shall be elected by majority vote for the Senator candidate of each division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-5-vacancy-in-the-senate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 5. Vacancy in The Senate&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Upon vacancy in The Senate, the Election Committee will appoint the next highest voted candidate from the previous election to office and The Senate will approve them by a majority vote. A successor shall serve for the remainder of the term.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Should a Representative position go unfilled and is also unable to be filled by previously stated vacancy procedures, the Representative position will remain empty. In tandem with the Fall General Election, a vote for the unfilled Representative position will be initiated in conjunction with the elections for the Freshman Senator position to serve the remainder of the term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-6-procedures&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 6. Procedures&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;No bill shall become law unless a Senator introduces the bill, the bill is read, and (during a subsequent meeting) the bill passes by vote of the Senate. Reference Article III, Section 7, Part a for vote requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;No bill shall become law without the signature of the Student Body President, except when the Student Body President has not vetoed the bill within seven (7) days after presentment, in which case the bill shall become law.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The University President or the University President’s designee may veto a proposed law. The Student Body President must notify the Senate President in writing no later than ten (10) days after receiving the veto stating the reasons for the University President’s veto.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Student Body Treasurer shall have veto equal with that of the Student Body President in all matters concerning Budget approval and revisions to said budget. The Student Body Treasurer shall have exclusive veto in matters concerning appropriations from Special Request Funds.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Any Bill which the Student Body President and Treasurer choose to veto, shall be considered as having been vetoed once.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A vetoed bill may be enacted notwithstanding the veto of the Student Body President or Treasurer if it is read a third time in full and passed by a super majority vote of the members of The Senate present and voting at a regular meeting after receiving the document of the written reason of why the Student Body President or Treasurer enacted the veto.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Quorum necessary to conduct business shall be one-third (1/3) of the total Senate membership. For further clarifications, see The Senate Handbook.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Legislation of The Senate shall only be classified as:
		&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bill of Law&lt;/b&gt; – Subject to Veto.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Budget&lt;/b&gt; – Primary or subsidiary budgets, of which all budgets shall be considered bills of law and subject to veto as described in this section.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Special Request Authorization&lt;/b&gt; – An appropriation from special request funds requiring a super majority vote for enactment subject to veto as described in this section.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Directive&lt;/b&gt; – An order requiring a majority vote for enactment that advises, orders, or prescribes the method for an SGA Member to fulfill a duty provided for in the Constitution and is not subject to veto.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Order to Action&lt;/b&gt; – A directive requiring a super majority vote which mandates that any SGA Affiliate to act on any action that SGA has previously assigned them.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resolution&lt;/b&gt; – An expression of the sentiment of The Senate requiring a super majority vote for passage and not subject to veto.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Immediate Action Clause&lt;/b&gt; – The Senate will have the authority to pass any legislation in the same Official Meeting in which it is presented. This subsection expires midnight on March 4th 2015, at which time this clause becomes unusable and unextendable for further use. The power of the Senate to pass legislature is returned to the power specified in &lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article III, Section 6, Part a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Senate shall also exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-7-powers-duties-and-limitations&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 7. Powers, Duties, and Limitations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enact, Constitutional bylaws to be known as Student Body Statutes by majority vote, with the exception of bylaws concerning elections, which shall require a super majority vote of the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Express the will and/or sentiments of The Senate in Resolution form.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Propose and act on Constitutional Amendments.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Provide for the compilation and publication of legislation.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Advise and consent, by an applicable vote, any and all appointments made by the Student Body President and Executive Branch.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Impeach Student Body officers, both elected and appointed, according to procedures described in Article VII.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Approve and allocate the fiscal budget of the Student Government Association, as provided by the Activity Fee.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allocate all student funds, as provided by the Activity Fee.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Establish its own meeting times and operate under Roberts Rules of Parliamentary Procedure.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Establish means through which the Student Body can actively participate in the formulation of policies affecting the students of the Florida Polytechnic University.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Override a veto by the Student Body President by a super majority vote of the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Request a review of a veto of the Student Body President by a Student Affairs designated official by a majority vote of The Senate. This is asking the official advice and clarification on the veto of the Student Body President.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Override a second veto by the Student Body President with super majority vote and refer the legislation to the University President for ultimate review and decision. The President of the University shall have twenty-one (21) days from the time the Office of the University President receives the legislation to veto or sign measures passed by The Senate. If the University President fails to reply within the timeframe, the law shall not pass.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Issue subpoenas by a majority vote of The Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Assemble in open meetings at least twice a month, for the deliberation of legislation and the business of the Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Call for a referendum of the Student Body through a super majority vote on a resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Create and appoint committees, or commissions, not provided in this Constitution, if deemed necessary, provided that these bodies do not contravene with the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enforce specified and pre-stated standards for clubs, organizations, and committees to maintain their SGA sponsorship and funding. This will be specified in The Senate Handbook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-8-prohibitions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 8. Prohibitions&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate shall not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enact any law that abridges its powers delegated by the constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appropriate funds for a period of more than one (1) year.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Infringe the secrecy of the ballot in any Student Body election.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Deny scheduled speaking privileges or recognized speaking privileges in an official Senate meeting to the Student Body, SGA Affiliates, and Faculty until recognized.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Deny unscheduled speaking privileges to Executive Director of the Honor Code Administration, any University Administrative Officer, College Dean, Student Body Chief of Staff, or Chief Justice Meet in a closed session.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Change the dates of Student Body elections in the six (6) weeks before the scheduled election.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Change the election laws during the three (3) weeks before the scheduled election to be effective for that election.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enact any law embracing more than one (1) subject and matter properly connected to that subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-iv-executive-branch&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article IV: Executive Branch&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-executive-power&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Executive Power&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All executive powers of the Student Body shall be vested in a Student Body President, Student Body Vice President, Student Body Treasurer, and Student Body Chief of Staff, who will be known as the SGA Executive Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-election&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Election&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SGA Executive Board, shall be chosen in the spring general election by a majority of the Student Body voting in the election, and shall serve for one-year (1) terms as provided for by the Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-vacancy-in-executive-offices&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Vacancy in Executive Offices&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon vacancy in the office of Student Body President, the Student Body Vice President shall fill the position. A vacancy in any executive position other than the President will be filled by the runner up of the election previous, pending approval of the Senate as stated in &lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article III, Section 5, Part r&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt; who shall serve for the remainder of the term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-powers-of-the-student-body-president&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4. Powers of the Student Body President&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body President shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the chief executive officer of the Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Take care that Code of Conduct is faithfully executed.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Have the power to veto legislation as provided for by the Constitution as seen in Article III, Section 6, Part b.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Present to The Senate, each term of the University, a State of the Campus message.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Create and appoint committees, or commissions, not provided in this Constitution, if deemed necessary, provided that these bodies do not contravene with the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Convene special meetings of The Senate, if deemed necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary. The Student Body President also has the authority to approve or reject the appointments made by the other members of the SGA Executive Board.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint a Student Honor Code Executive Director to be a member of the Cabinet.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the Student Body’s official representative to the University’s Board of Trustees and the Florida Student Association.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-5-executive-departments&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 5. Executive Departments&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Executive departments may be established by The Senate, with the Head of each department to be appointed by the Student Body President and confirmed with at least a concurrence of a majority of The Senate. Officers of the executive departments shall be responsible to the Student Body President for the execution of their duties and shall be subject to removal by the Student Body President. The terms of the Heads of the executive departments shall expire concurrently with the expiration of the regular terms of the elected executive officials. The Heads of the executive departments may appoint subordinate aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-6-cabinet&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 6. Cabinet&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There shall be a Cabinet, consisting of the heads of the executive departments and other Student Government officials that The Senate shall provide by law to be Cabinet-Level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-7-powers-of-the-student-body-vice-president&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 7. Powers of the Student Body Vice President&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body Vice President shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the Chief Services Officer of the Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Assist the Student Body President in the conduct of government.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise the powers and duties of the Student Body President in their absence.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Attend meetings of all service committees and entities under Student Government to stay in communication with these departments and organizations. If the Vice President cannot personally attend, the Vice President shall appoint an aide to go in their stead.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-8-powers-of-the-student-body-treasurer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 8. Powers of the Student Body Treasurer&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body Treasurer shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the Chief Financial Officer of the Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Keep complete and accurate accounts of all Student Body funds on deposit with the University Comptroller.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Have the power to veto legislation as provided for by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sign all requisitions on Student Body funds on order of The Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Assist the Student Body President and Student Body Vice President in the conduct of government.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Attend all official meetings of the Audit and Budget Committee as a non-voting member.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-9-powers-of-the-student-chief-of-staff&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 9. Powers of the Student Chief of Staff&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body Secretary shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the Chief Organizational Officer of the Student Body&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Record SGA Executive Board and official Senate meeting minutes or appoint an aide to do so in their stead.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Post minutes of the SGA meeting in a public forum.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Email minutes of SGA Executive Board and official Senate meetings to members.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Send reminders regarding meetings and events out to the SGA Executive Board and Senate members.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Take attendance at All SGA Executive Board and official Senate meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Assist the SGA Executive Board in the conduct of government.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Communicate regularly with Senate leadership through appropriate methods such as attending Senate leadership meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-v-judicial-branch&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article V: Judicial Branch&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-judicial-powers&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Judicial Powers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All judicial power of the Student Body shall be vested in the Judicial Branch, and such other tribunals as are established by law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-administration&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Administration&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice and procedure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court shall be the chief administrative officer of the judicial system.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Judicial Branch shall adopt its own internal rules of practice and procedure for itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-judicial-board&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Judicial Board&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;dl&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;A. Organization&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;The Judicial Board shall consist of the Chief Justice and up to six justices. The Chief Justice shall preside over the Judicial Board. Simple majority of members shall constitute a quorum. The concurrence in judgment of a simple majority members shall be necessary for a decision. The Judicial Board shall provide in its rules of practice and procedure the process for assigning qualified students to temporary duty as substitutes, where recusals for cause would prohibit the Judicial Board from convening because of the requirements of this section. To be eligible to be assigned to temporary duty, a person must meet the minimal qualifications of membership on the Judicial Board. The Chief Justice shall be responsible for selecting temporary Justices and shall assign an Associate Justice this duty if the Chief Justice is subject to recusal.&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;B. Jurisdiction&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;The Supreme Court:
			&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Shall interpret any provision of the Constitution or any law that is written within:
					&lt;ol type=&quot;i&quot;&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Upon any written petition of five percent (5%) of the total Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Request of the Student Body President.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ol&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Shall, upon written petition of any member of the Student Body, and for good and fair cause shown as determined by the Chief Justice and to be consistent with the internal procedures of the supreme court, order any SGA Affiliate or any person who has attended an SGA sponsored event or activity, to appear in front of the court. This shall only occur if the student performs any act that violates this Constitution, any applicable Code of Conduct, State, or Federal Law.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Shall hear appeals from tribunals and lower courts as established by the Supreme Court.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;May issue any writ necessary to the complete exercise of its jurisdiction.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Will suspend and terminate the position of any SGA Officer convicted of a Felony in an official State or Federal Court during their term in office.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Shall maintain a permanent election result file of every student body election.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;C. Subpoena Power&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;The Supreme Court shall have the power to issue subpoenas and subpoena duces tecum directed at any SGA Affiliate, returnable before the Supreme Court or any tribunal it designates.&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;D. Eligibility and Tenure&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;No person shall be eligible to hold the office of Chief Justice or Associate Justice of the Supreme Court unless that person has successfully completed first year writing requirements, and attained a total cumulative 2.50 grade point average. The Chief Justice and Associate Justices of the Supreme Court shall have the right to remain in office without reappointment until they are awarded a degree.&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;E. Vacancy in Office&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;Whenever a vacancy occurs in the office of the Chief Justice or Associate Justice of the Judicial Branch, the Student Body President shall fill the vacancy by appointment, subject to a super majority confirmation vote by The Senate.&lt;/dd&gt;
	&lt;dt&gt;&lt;b&gt;F. Clerk and Marshal&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/dt&gt;
		&lt;dd&gt;The Chief Justice may appoint a clerk and a marshal for the Supreme Court who shall hold office during the pleasure of the Chief Justice and perform such duties pertinent for to the court as the Chief Justice directs.&lt;/dd&gt;
&lt;/dl&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-vi-elections&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article VI: ELECTIONS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-qualifications-to-vote&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Qualifications to Vote&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body shall comprise the electorate. Each member of the electorate shall be entitled to a single vote per election or item in Student Body elections.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-fall-general-election&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2: Fall General Election&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Fall general election shall occur on the Tuesday and Wednesday of the sixth (6) week of the Fall term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-spring-general-election&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3: Spring General Election&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first day of the Spring general election shall be the last Tuesday in March and the second day shall be the succeeding calendar day.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-voting-method&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4: Voting Method&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The voting method used in elections shall be outlined in the Student Body Statutes.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-5-election-conflicts&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 5: Election Conflicts&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If any hour of any day of a general election conflicts with a religious or school holiday or if any other reasonable conflict exists, The Senate shall, by Resolution, designate different days for the affected election or elections. They may also, by Resolution, order the Elections Committee to designate a special voting time for a religious group to vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-6-validation-of-election-results&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 6: Validation of Election Results&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate shall validate general elections in the next regularly scheduled Senate meeting.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-7-time-of-assuming-office&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 7: Time of Assuming Office&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;a)	Campus wide officers elected in the Spring general election in races requiring a majority vote shall assume office on the last regularly scheduled class day and shall serve one (1) year.
b)	The Senators shall assume office at the first meeting following validation by The Senate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-8-qualifications-for-office&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 8: Qualifications for Office&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless a more restrictive standard is stated in the Constitution, to be eligible for an office within student government, a student must have and maintain an overall 2.5 grade point average on all work attempted as a member of the Student Body and conform to all requirements imposed by the Division of Student Affairs. Candidates for the offices of the Executive Branch shall have completed a minimum of three (3) academic semesters, excluding summer semesters, at Florida Polytechnic University. &lt;em&gt;This will take effect in the Spring of 2016.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-vii-impeachment&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article VII: IMPEACHMENT&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-the-recall-and-remove-procedure&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. The Recall and Remove Procedure&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A recall petition signed by one-eighth (1/8) of the total Student Body initiates a referendum in the Student Body. At least one-fourth (1/4) of the Student Body must vote in the referendum or the elected official retains office. The result will go in favor of the majority vote.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%; margin-right:5%&quot;&gt;
	&lt;em&gt;“The grounds for removal of a [Student Government Official] by petition must be expressly contained in the petition and are limited to the following: malfeasance, misfeasance, neglect of duty, incompetence, permanent inability to perform official duties, or conviction of a felony. The referendum must be held no later than sixty (60) days after the filing of the petition.”&lt;/em&gt; - State of Florida Statutes, Section 1004.26 (4)(b)
&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-persons-who-may-be-impeached&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2: Persons Who May Be Impeached&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SGA Executive Board, Supervisor of Elections, Heads of Cabinet or Agency Heads, Cabinet Directors for the Executive Branch, all Student Government Officials of the Judicial Branch, and members of a Constitution revision commission may be impeached for misfeasance, malfeasance, nonfeasance, abuse of power, or conviction of a criminal offense while in office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-filing-of-impeachment-resolution&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3: Filing of impeachment resolution&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate shall provide in its rules of procedure the definition of the filing date of an impeachment resolution, provided that a minimum of one (1) Senator must co-file the impeachment resolution, and that the affected person must receive a true copy of the impeachment resolution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-impeachment-body&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4: Impeachment Body&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate class, either the Fall or Spring elected and appointed Senators, that has served the greater amount of time on the filing date of an impeachment resolution shall be the body that impeaches. The Senate president shall preside over the impeachment body and may vote if The Senate president is a member of that Senate class. A super majority vote of the membership of the impeachment body shall be required in order to impeach.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-5-suspension-upon-impeachment&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 5: Suspension upon impeachment&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A person impeached by the impeachment body shall be suspended from office until acquitted or found guilty by the trial body. The Student Body President, unless impeached, may, by appointment, fill the office until completion of the trial. If the Student Body President is impeached, succession shall be as stated in Article IV, Section 3.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-6-trial-body&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 6: Trial body&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All impeachments by the impeachment body shall be tried by the trial body which shall be the Senate class that has served the least amount of time on the filing date of an impeachment resolution. The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court shall preside unless a member of the judiciary is being impeached, in which event the Student Body President shall preside. The presiding officer shall have no vote. A super majority vote of the membership of the trial body shall be required for conviction.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-7-effect-of-conviction&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 7: Effect of conviction&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Judgment of conviction in cases of impeachment shall remove the offender from office and, at the discretion of the trial body, may include disqualification to hold any elected or appointed student government office in the future. Conviction or acquittal shall not affect the civil or criminal responsibility of the person.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-viii-amendments&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article VIII: AMENDMENTS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-proposal-by-the-senate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1: Proposal by The Senate&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate may introduce amendments to the Constitution in a meeting, and during a subsequent meeting the amendment is passed by a super majority vote of The Senate. This shall occur no later than twenty-eight (28) days before the ratification election. Each amendment proposed shall embrace only one (1) subject and matter directly connected to that subject.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-proposal-by-initiative&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2: Proposal by Initiative&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Students may propose amendments to the constitution upon a submission of a petition to the Chief Justice of the Judicial Branch, joined by one-eighth (1/8) petition of the electorate no later than twenty-eight (28) days before the ratification election. Each amendment proposed shall embrace only one (1) subject and matter directly connected to that subject. The Elections Commission shall have the authority to determine if the petition has an accurate summary, and if it determines it is not, to modify the summary so as to be accurate. After making such determination, it shall, in all cases, forward the petition to the Supervisor of Elections for inclusion on the ballot. Such determinations shall be subject to the Review of the Supreme Court.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-requirement-for-ratification&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3: Requirement for Ratification&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;A three-fifths (3/5) approval vote of those voting in the Spring general election is necessary to ratify all constitutional amendments. Unless otherwise specified in the amendment, a ratified amendment shall be effective at 8:00 p.m. on the first day of May following the Spring general election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-publication-requirement&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4: Publication Requirement&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The text and summary of all amendments shall be published in a campus-wide media publication one (1) week before and on both days of the election.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-ix-miscellaneous&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article IX: MISCELLANEOUS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-rules-of-construction&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Rules of construction.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Unless otherwise qualified in the text, the following rules of construction shall apply to the Constitution:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;References to a specific University department or position shall also include the successor department or position.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;In situations where different provisions of this constitution conflict, the more specific provision applies to the extent of the conflict.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Day&lt;/b&gt;: A single date on the Gregorian Calendar&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Exclusionary&lt;/b&gt;: An exclusionary position is one (1) which must be held exclusive from all other exclusionary positions within Student Government&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Executive Board&lt;/b&gt;: “E-Board” Any positions elected by a club including but not limited to: President, Vice President, Treasurer, and Secretary&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Executive Branch&lt;/b&gt;: All positions under the Student Body President including, cabinet members, cabinet heads, agency heads, and the SGA Executive Board&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;First Week&lt;/b&gt;: First week of an academic term, drop/add period for students&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Full-Time Student&lt;/b&gt;: As defined by the University Registrar, to be a full-time student in the Fall and Spring Semesters of their term. Summer terms are excluded from this requirement&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Funding Fee&lt;/b&gt;: The revenue generating fee from which SGA makes appropriations. Currently, the funding fee is known as the Activity &amp;amp; Service fee&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Judicial Branch&lt;/b&gt;: Includes the Supreme Court and all other Florida Polytechnic tribunals. This branch is overseen by the Chief Justice of the Supreme Court&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Majority Vote&lt;/b&gt;: One-half (1/2) of all votes, an exact vote of 1/2 will go in favor of the nays&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Non-Exclusionary&lt;/b&gt;: Any position in Student Government which can be simultaneously held with any other non-exclusionary or one (1) exclusionary position&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Of The Membership&lt;/b&gt;: The total number of authorized seats in the body&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Primary Budget&lt;/b&gt;: The budget from which student government appropriates revenue generated by the funding fee for a fiscal year&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGA Affiliate&lt;/b&gt;: Any student holding an Exclusionary or Non-exclusionary positions or any student who holds an executive position in a club receiving SGA funding&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGA Executive Board&lt;/b&gt;: The Student Body President, Student Body Vice President, Student Body Treasurer, and Student Body Chief of Staff&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;SGA Member&lt;/b&gt;: Any student holding an Exclusionary or Non-exclusionary positions&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Student&lt;/b&gt;: Any person currently enrolled in a minimum of one (1) credit hour&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Student Body&lt;/b&gt;: All students in attendance at Florida Polytechnic University, including SGA officers and members&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Student Body Officer-Elect&lt;/b&gt;: A person elected who has not yet assumed office. A person that a student body officer-elect has appointed may not assume office until the student body officer- elect assumes office, even if the appointed person has been confirmed by The Senate&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Student Body Official&lt;/b&gt;: Any person who holds an exclusionary position within student government&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Student Government Association (SGA)&lt;/b&gt;: Governs and represents the Student Body. Its actions not otherwise limited by Code of Conduct supersede those of all other student organizations&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Subsidiary Budget&lt;/b&gt;: All budgets, excluding the primary budget. Currently, the subsidiary budgets are the organizational budget and the special events budget, but shall also include all future budgets except the primary budget&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Super Majority Vote&lt;/b&gt;: Two-thirds (2/3) of all votes, an exact vote of 2/3 will go in favor of the nays&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Veto&lt;/b&gt;: A constitutional right to reject a decision or proposal made by a law-making body&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-vacancy-in-office&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2: Vacancy in Office&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Vacancy in office shall occur upon creation of an office, graduation without immediate re- matriculation, death, removal from office, resignation, failure to maintain the required residency or classification, or failure to qualify by the first day of the term of office. No vacancy is created in the event that a Senator no longer meets the classification of their Representative position; they have the right to finish their session in office.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-laws-preserved&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3: Laws Preserved&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All laws enacted under the provisions of the School Year 2014-2015 Constitution, as subsequently amended, and not contrary to the provisions of this Constitution, shall remain in full effect until they expire by their terms or are repealed under the provisions of this Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-x-ratification-of-constitution&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article X: RATIFICATION OF CONSTITUTION&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-process&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Process.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color: rebeccapurple;&quot;&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;The below authorities representing their department or branch sign below to acknowledge that the proper addition of the amendment(s) and the staying of unchanged material is correct&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;b&gt;Title&lt;/b&gt;: 06-05: Fall and Spring Class Amendment&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;b&gt;Brief:&lt;/b&gt; This bill will amend the Student Body constitution to create a fall and spring class. This will help the students because in the current system they vote in the spring for where they believe they will live in the fall and the same thought is used when voting for class representatives. Representatives will start their role if they are elected shortly after the election date.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;b&gt;Title&lt;/b&gt; 06-06: Voting Method Amendment&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;big&gt;&lt;b&gt;Brief:&lt;/b&gt; This bill will amend the Student Body constitution to remove the run-off election to be replaced with a voting method section. This will allow the student body to choose what method of voting they want to use for elections. Ranked Choice Voting or similar methods may be chosen for future elections.&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/big&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Constitution" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Title VI - Elections</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleVI/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title VI - Elections" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Statutes/title_vi</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleVI/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Last Revised: 04.08.20&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-6-elections&quot;&gt;Title 6 Elections&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 600: Elections Code of Ethics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 601: Elections Committee&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 602: Candidacy&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 603: Campaigning&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 604: Voting&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 605: Election Results&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 606: Student Government Association Orientation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 607: Apportionment&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 608: Voting Method&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 609: Marking a Ballot&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
	#legal-list { 
		counter-reset: section; 
		counter-increment: section -1;
	}
	#legal-list h3:before { 
		content: &quot;60&quot; counter(section) &quot;. &quot;;
		counter-increment: section;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
	#legal-list ol {
		counter-reset: clause;
		list-style: none outside none;
		text-indent: -1em;
	}
	#legal-list ol li { counter-increment: clause; }
	#legal-list ol li:before {
		content: &quot;60&quot; counter(section) &quot;.&quot; counters(clause, &quot;.&quot;) &quot;. &quot;;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;html&gt;
&lt;body id=&quot;legal-list&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Elections Code of Ethics&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Voters will not have their opinions influenced while they are voting&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;No person is allowed to defame written or verbal campaign material&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates are not allowed to falsify information&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;No candidate will commit bribery, extortion, blackmail, slander, or libel during their campaigning.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;No A&amp;amp;S funded material will be used to campaign.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates may not commit any act of violence against any member of a campaign &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;No candidate may withhold financial records or changes to the campaign budget  &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;No candidate will condone or authorize the destruction of another campaign’s materials&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;No one will attempt to cast more than one vote or tamper with voting devices or software.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;No candidate will take advantage of the official capacity of their position (if an employee of the University) for their own personal campaign&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates may not campaign in an area that causes discomfort to the public, student body, faculty, or staff&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Elections Committee&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Election Committee (EC) will be an unbiased party loosely attached to SGA with the purpose of creating and running a fair election.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Election Committee will keep a Rules of Operation to further define and lay out procedure for content from Title VI of SGA Statutes.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Revisions to the Rules of Operation are subject to approval by a majority of the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Elections Committee will consist of an Elections Chair that has the following responsibilities:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Validate candidates&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Set deadlines for candidates not outlined in the governing documents. &lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Inform candidates of the election rules and regulations through a Meeting of the Candidates. &lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Announce locations and operating hours of all official polling stations at least five (5) calendar days prior to any election.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Announce the modification of an election due to the university closing or problems with the voting system.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Publicly verify and approve the results of the election&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Announce the results of the General Election and/or Run-Off Election &lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Propose amendments to the Election Committee Rules of Procedures when seen fit&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Update the Senate about Elections upon request&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Appoint/remove persons to/from the EC. &lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Oversee violations brought to the Elections Committee&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;A list of succession will be listed in the Elections Committee Rules of Operation.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Members of the Election Committee are not allowed to run for office or currently hold office in SGA&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Election Committee must have a minimum of 4 voting members including the Elections Chair who will have a vote in the event of a tie&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Candidacy&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates must agree to abide by all rules, regulations, and procedures found within Title 6 of the statutes and within the Elections Committee Rules of Operation&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates must submit an application package to the Elections Committee by the deadline as outlined in the Elections Committee Rules of Operation.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The application package will contain the following:&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Position the candidate is running for&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Declaration of Intent&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Other material deemed relevant to the election by the EC&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Elections Committee will verify that all candidates meet the minimum qualifications for their position as defined in the SGA Constitution, Statutes, and other governing documents&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates may withdraw from the election by submitting a withdrawal form to the EC, at no penalty to them. Candidates that withdraw from the election may not reapply to the same election from which they have withdrawn&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Campaigning&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Campaign Period shall begin two (2) weeks prior to voting and will end on the last day of voting.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Students may not actively or passively campaign within 50 yards (150 feet) in any direction of an Official Polling location forty-eight (48) hours prior to their election.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates are not allowed to use campaigning material not approved by the Election Committee&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates running for the executive branch may endorse other candidates running for positions of the Executive Branch.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates running for the Executive Branch may not endorse members of the Legislative Branch.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates running for the legislative branch may not endorse other candidates. &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Campaign spending over $200 is not permitted. All donations must be reported to the Elections Committee and must be reported publicly.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates may have campaign staff. This staff must also abide by the Election Code of Ethics. Campaign staff will not be paid.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Restricted Location of advertisements may be specified in the Elections Committee Rules of Operation.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates may campaign in locations including but not limited to
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Student spaces&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Classes with permission of the professor&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Town halls&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Candidates campaigning at an RSO must abide by the following stipulations:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The RSO e-Board has given permission to campaign at a meeting via a majority vote of the e-Board. &lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Notification of approval must be sent to the Elections Committee at least 72 hours prior to the meeting. &lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Notification must also include the positions being campaigned for.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;All candidates for positions accepted must have at least 48-hours&apos; notice from the Election Committee that the meeting is taking place and have opportunity to campaign in the same meeting.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The RSO e-Board does not endorse any specific candidate (I.e. through social media, emails, etc.)&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;One member of the Elections Committee (or their designated representative) should be present at the meeting for the purpose of ensuring that every candidate is afforded the same opportunity.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Voting&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;All Florida Poly students have the right to vote in SGA elections.  &lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Changes to students’ voting status for the purpose of college selection shall only be considered if the change took place at least thirty (30) calendar days before voting opens.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Write-in candidates may occur in the fall and spring election for positions that go unfilled. All write-ins shall be subject to the Elections Code of Ethics.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Elections Committee must verify that winning Write-in candidates did not campaign actively before the election and that winning Write-in candidates fulfill all requirements for the position they were written-in for.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Elections Results&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Elections Committee will present the results of elections to the next scheduled Senate meeting to be verified by the Senate with a majority vote.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Upon verification, the Elections Committee will send out the results via email to the student body no more than 5 business days after they are verified. If they are not sent out within 5 business days, the Senate will send out the results.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Student Government Association Orientation&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;All elected candidates will attend an orientation before taking office
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The orientation will take place after the spring and fall elections&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;If a candidate is unable to attend, the organizer of the orientation shall give the elected candidate all required information&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Apportionment&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Senate shall reapportion itself once per year at least six (6) weeks before the date of the spring election to be effective for the spring academic term and subsequent fall academic term&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Office of Institutional Research estimated student body population for the next academic year will be used for reapportionment&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;If the estimated student body is not available at the time of reapportionment, the current student body population will be used&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The estimated or current total student body population will be rounded to the nearest 240 students for the purpose of allocating the total number of Senate seats&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Voting Method&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;For the officer positions of Student Body President, Student Body Vice President, Student Body Treasurer, Student Body Chief of Staff, and all single-seat Senate races, the ballots shall be counted by the method of ranked choice voting if there are more than two (2) candidates. First-Past-The-Post voting “majority vote” will be used in that scenario&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Ranked Choice Voting counting procedure
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The initial round of counting shall be a count of the first choices marked on each ballot. If any candidate receives a majority of the first choices, that candidate shall be declared the winner&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;If no candidate receives a majority of first choices, there shall be a second round of counting.  The last-place candidate shall be eliminated, and all the continuing ballots shall be recounted.  Each continuing ballot shall be counted as one vote for that ballot’s highest ranked advancing candidate.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;If no candidate receives a majority at the second round of counting, there shall be a third round of counting, continuing in the manner prescribed above.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The process of eliminating the last-place candidates and recounting all the continuing ballots shall continue until one candidate receives a majority of the votes in a round.  The candidate who receives a majority of the votes in a round shall be declared the winner, pending ratification.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;When a ballot does not list a preference for any given round, it shall not be counted in that round or any subsequent round.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;If there are not sufficient second and lower choices for any candidate to receive a majority, the candidate with the highest number of votes shall be declared the winner, pending ratification.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;When a ballot becomes an exhausted ballot, it shall not be counted in that round or any subsequent round for that position.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;For the officer positions of multi-seat senate races, the ballots shall be counted by the method of multi-winner ranked choice voting&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Multi-Winner Ranked Choice Voting procedures
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The threshold for each multi-winner race is determined by using the number of open positions and adding one to that number to determine a denominating number. Then taking the total number of valid ballots cast and dividing by that denominating number. The resulting number is then increased by one.
					&lt;ol&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;((Total number of votes cast for that position)/(number of open positions + 1))+1&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ol&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Counting the ballot
					&lt;ol&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;The initial round of counting shall be a count of the first choices marked on each ballot. Any candidates who reaches the necessary threshold after the first round of counting are declared elected
							&lt;ol&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;A candidate elected in the initial round shall not receive any further ballots&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Any candidate reaching threshold shall not receive any more ballots&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;/ol&gt;
						&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;In the event that the initial round did not result in electing candidates to fill all open positions then the remaining positons shall be determined by the following:
							&lt;ol&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Votes above the threshold for the elected candidates are redistributed to the candidates marked next in preference using surplus transfer (see that section).&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;/ol&gt;
						&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;If, after transferring the surplus, a candidate’s votes rise to the threshold, that candidate is declared elected.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Surplus transfer is repeated until all votes have been transferred.  If a position is still open, then the candidate that has the lowest number of votes is eliminated and their ballots are counted for the next indicated choice on their ballot. This process continues until no remaining candidates reach the threshold or the number of eliminated candidates precludes any further election.&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ol&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Transferring the surplus
					&lt;ol&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Ballots cast for candidates whom met threshold are sorted by pile, by the elected candidate.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;A surplus number is determined for each elected candidate by taking the total number of votes for that candidate and subtracting the threshold number.&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Using that surplus number, ballots are removed from that candidates stack and distributed to other candidates as follows:
							&lt;ol&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Each pile is recounted to determine the number of next votes for any candidates not yet elected.&lt;/li&gt;
								&lt;li&gt;Using those numbers, the remaining candidates are given a portion of the votes relative to the voting share reflected by the recount
									&lt;ol&gt;
										&lt;li&gt;(Next choice/total votes for that candidate) *surplus number&lt;/li&gt;
									&lt;/ol&gt;
								&lt;/li&gt;
							&lt;/ol&gt;
						&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ol&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Marking a ballot&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;For multi candidate races - voters are to rank their choices in order of preference – 1st choice, 2nd choice, 3rd choice, and so on.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;To be valid, a ballot must be marked with sequential numbers&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Statutes" /><summary type="html">Last Revised: 04.08.20 Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Title I - Introduction to SGA Statutes</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleI/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title I - Introduction to SGA Statutes" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Statutes/title_i</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleI/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Last Revised: 6-28-19&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-1-introduction-to-sga-statutes&quot;&gt;Title 1 Introduction to SGA Statutes&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 100: System of Student Government Association (SGA) Statutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 101: Amendments to the Student Government Association Statutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 102: Enforcement of the Student Government Association Statutes&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 103: Symbols&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 104: Definitions of Terms in the Student Government Association Statutes&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
	#legal-list { 
		counter-reset: section; 
		counter-increment: section -1;
	}
	#legal-list h3:before { 
		content: &quot;10&quot; counter(section) &quot;. &quot;;
		counter-increment: section;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
	#legal-list ol {
		counter-reset: clause;
		list-style: none outside none;
		text-indent: -1em;
	}
	#legal-list ol li { counter-increment: clause; }
	#legal-list ol li:before {
		content: &quot;10&quot; counter(section) &quot;.&quot; counters(clause, &quot;.&quot;) &quot;. &quot;;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;html&gt;
  &lt;body id=&quot;legal-list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;System of Student Government Association (SGA) Statutes&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Objective
        &lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;This chapter serves to outline the structure and jurisdiction of the Student Government Association statutes.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Structure
      	&lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;These statutes shall be organized into titles and chapters, which may then be further subdivided via a decimal system.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
      &lt;li&gt;Jurisdiction
      	&lt;ol&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;These statutes shall describe and identify Student Government Association entities, processes, and procedures.&lt;/li&gt;
          &lt;li&gt;Student Government Association statutes shall not conflict with any Federal laws, State laws, University policies, or the SGA Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
        &lt;/ol&gt;
      &lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Amendments to the Student Government Association Statutes&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Objective
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;This Chapter outlines procedures for amending and maintaining SGA Statutes&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Amendments
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;An amendment to any part of the SGA Statutes may be proposed in the form of a Statutory Bill to the SGA Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;A Statutory Bill that is passed by the Senate shall become an act upon the approval of the Student Body President or upon a successful override of a Presidential Veto.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Distribution
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;All Acts shall be distributed by the Senate President Pro Tempore via hand-delivery to all leaders of the Executive, Legislative, and Judicial branches within five (5) business days of their successful passage through the legislative process.
    			&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Upkeep
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;There shall be an official record of current and past SGA statutes that is compiled, maintained, and published by the Officer of Standards and Enforcement.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;This official record shall include all statutory amendments presented to the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Enforcement of the Student Government Association Statutes&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Enforcement
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;These statutes shall be applicable to and enforceable upon officers and associated officers of the Student Government Association and entities described within these statutes.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Symbols&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Symbols
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The official SGA logo will be the logo that is used by the majority of SGA at any point in time.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The official SGA seal will be the seal that is used by the majority of SGA at any point in time.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Definitions of Terms in the Student Government Association Statutes&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Objective
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;This chapter serves to define acronyms and terms used throughout these statutes that would otherwise be unclear or ambiguous.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;A&amp;amp;S Fee:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The activity and service fee, established by Florida law, and allocated by the legislative branch towards activities and services.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Academic Semester:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The Florida Polytechnic University Fall, Spring, Summer A, Summer B, or Summer C semester.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Bill:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; An allocation or an amendment to SGA statutes that has been sent to the Legislative Branch that has not fully gone through the legislative process.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Business Day:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; An entire weekday (Monday through Friday), starting at 9 AM and ending at 5 PM, and excluding any days in which classes are not being held.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Due Process:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The conduct of any proceeding wherein there is fair treatment to all parties involved.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Officers:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Any person that is a member of a body by virtue of their position.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;SGA Affiliate:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Any person that is a member of a body associated with SGA by virtue of their position. As defined by the Constitution&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Fiscal Year:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The year starting on July 1st and ending on June 30th.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;General Body Meeting:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Meetings as defined by SOP, Handbook, Statute of any respective body.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Majority:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; More than half.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Majority Vote:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The affirmative vote of the majority of the present voting members.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;On Campus:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Defined by any property or facility owned or operated by Florida Polytechnic University.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Quorum:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The presence of at least one-third (1/3) of a body’s total number of voting members, except where specified otherwise in a more restrictive manner.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;SGA Constitution:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The Constitution of the Student Body of Florida Polytechnic University.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;SGA:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Student Government Association.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;SGA Official (Student Body Official):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Any member of SGA who is elected by the Student Body or confirmed by the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;SGA Term:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The period of time an SGA Official serves in their respective office.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Student Government:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; Student Government Association.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Standard Operating Procedure (SOP):&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; A document detailing the inner workings of an SGA entity.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Student Body:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; All enrolled students of Florida Polytechnic University.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Supermajority Vote:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; The affirmative vote of at least two-thirds (2/3) of the entire body of voting members.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;&lt;u&gt;Exclusionary Position:&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/b&gt; An exclusionary position is one that must be held exclusive from all other exclusionary positions within a student government.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
  &lt;/body&gt; 
&lt;/html&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Statutes" /><summary type="html">Last Revised: 6-28-19 Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Title II - Officer Procedures</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleII/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title II - Officer Procedures" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Statutes/title_ii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleII/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Last Revised: 10/28/2019&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-2-officer-procedures&quot;&gt;Title 2 Officer Procedures&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 200: Membership Eligibility&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 201: Hiring&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 202: Code of Ethics&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 203: Transparency&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 204: End of Term Procedures&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 205:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
	#legal-list { 
		counter-reset: section; 
		counter-increment: section -1;
	}
	#legal-list h3:before { 
		content: &quot;20&quot; counter(section) &quot;. &quot;;
		counter-increment: section;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
	#legal-list ol {
		counter-reset: clause;
		list-style: none outside none;
		text-indent: -1em;
	}
	#legal-list ol li { counter-increment: clause; }
	#legal-list ol li:before {
		content: &quot;20&quot; counter(section) &quot;.&quot; counters(clause, &quot;.&quot;) &quot;. &quot;;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;html&gt;
&lt;body id=&quot;legal-list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Membership Eligibility&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Objective
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;This chapter serves to outline requirements that make members eligible to serve in Student Government positions&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Requirements
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;All members of Student Government must meet the following qualifications
    				&lt;ol&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;Be a full-time student attending Florida Polytechnic University&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;Maintain grade point average requirements as specified in the constitution&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;Conform to requirements made by Student Development&lt;/li&gt;
    				&lt;/ol&gt;
    			&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Other branches may specify additional requirements for appointed and non-elected positions as stated in Title III, Title IV, or Title V for each respective branch.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Exclusionary Positions
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;All elected positions in the executive branch, legislative branch, and all appointed positions by the student body president are exclusionary positions&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Hiring&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Objective
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;This section is meant to create procedures for hiring SGA members that are not elected or members of the judicial branch, such as, chief justice or associate justice, to and receive financial compensation for their work&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Nominating Officers (NO)
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;A nominating officer is the officer that is seeking out a candidate to fill a position&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The student body president shall have the power to nominate students under this chapter&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The elections chair shall have the power to nominate students to positions within the Elections Committee&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The senate president shall have the power to nominate student aids in accordance with positions outlined in the Senate Handbook&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The chief justice shall have the power to nominate student aids in accordance with positions outlined in the Judicial Handbook&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Advertising
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;An open position’s NO shall determine when to start advertising for that position&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The NO shall prepare a job application, job description, and job qualifications&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The open position shall be advertised for, at minimum, five (5) days at the front of the SGA office&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Interviews
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The judicial branch will be responsible for reviewing the applications for the job advertised&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The judicial branch will interview, at minimum, the top three (3) candidates for the job, if there are over three (3) applicants&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The judicial branch will recommend an applicant to the NO based on the qualifications of the candidate as set forth by the position job description
    				&lt;ol&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;If the position in question resides in the Judicial Branch, the executive branch will follow the actions set forth in 201.4 as the interviewing body&lt;/li&gt;
    				&lt;/ol&gt;
    			&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Conformation
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The NO will send a final nomination along with the nominee’s application paperwork to the legislative branch&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;All nominations are subject to confirmation by the Senate&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The Senate shall confirm or reject applicable nominees within twenty (20) business days of their nomination or the position is confirmed by default&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;If rejected, the NO may appeal the rejection to the Senate with a supermajority vote&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Remuneration
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The following positions are required to be paid in accordance with Title VIII
    				&lt;ol&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;SGA President&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;SGA Vice President&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;SGA Treasurer&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;SGA Chief of Staff&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;Senate President&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;Senate Pro Tempore&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;Chief Justice&lt;/li&gt;
    				&lt;/ol&gt;
    			&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Other positions may also be paid through allocation in the SGA budget&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Code of Ethics&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Objective
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;This Code of Ethics is made to ensure that SGA and its members act in an impartial manner and to protect this SGA from unethical practices&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Standards of Conduct
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Conflicts of interest: no SGA official shall act on a matter that would benefit their own personal interests instead of, or over, SGA interests&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;No SGA affiliate will advise anyone to violate the SGA constitution or SGA statutes&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;No SGA affiliate will attempt to cover up a violation of the SGA constitution or SGA statutes&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;No individual in SGA and no activity sponsored by SGA will discriminate on the basis of gender identity or expression, race, ethnicity, creed, color, religion, sex, age, sexual orientation, national origin, marital status, parental status, disability, and any combination thereof&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;SGA affiliates will act in a manner as to not cause harm intentionally to others&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;SGA affiliates shall report any unethical practices they see within SGA&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Transparency&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The Florida Polytechnic University SGA shall follow all Florida Sunshine Laws&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;End of Term Procedures&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;End of Term
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Outgoing SGA officers shall be asked to conduct an exit interview with their replacement (if there is one) and the leader of the branch of which they were a member. In the event that the outgoing officer is the leader of the branch, the officer will just meet with their replacement&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Vacancy of Office
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;All officers vacating their position will be asked to write an exit interview and complete any requirements written in their branch’s statutes&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Statutes" /><summary type="html">Last Revised: 10/28/2019 Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Title III - The Executive Branch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleIII/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title III - The Executive Branch" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Statutes/title_iii</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleIII/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Last Revised: 4-3-19&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-3-the-executive-branch&quot;&gt;Title 3 The Executive Branch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 300: Executive Powers&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 301: Executive Branch Vacancies&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 302: Continuity&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 303: Powers of the President Elect&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 304: Transition Period&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 305: External Representation&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 306: Internal Representation and Communication&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
	#legal-list { 
		counter-reset: section; 
		counter-increment: section -1;
	}
	#legal-list h3:before { 
		content: &quot;30&quot; counter(section) &quot;. &quot;;
		counter-increment: section;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
	#legal-list ol {
		counter-reset: clause;
		list-style: none outside none;
		text-indent: -1em;
	}
	#legal-list ol li { counter-increment: clause; }
	#legal-list ol li:before {
		content: &quot;30&quot; counter(section) &quot;.&quot; counters(clause, &quot;.&quot;) &quot;. &quot;;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;html&gt;
&lt;body id=&quot;legal-list&quot;&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Executive Powers&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The powers of the executive branch are granted from the Student Body Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The Executive Branch shall
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Be the administrative arm of the Student Government Association.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Be responsible for the planning and execution of programs, projects, and services provided to the students through SGA.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Be responsive to student needs.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The Executive Branhc shall consist of:
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;President&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Vice-President&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Treasurer&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Chief of Staff&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Executive Cabinet&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Executive Staff&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The Executive Branch
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The President has the power to appoint and dismiss within the Executive Branch at their discretion. This does not include elected positions.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The President shall be responsible for all actions done within the Executive Branch with the exception being elected positions.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Administrative Authority
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The President may organize the Executive Branch as they deem necessary in accordance with the SGA Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The President must adopt Executive policies and procedures within one (1) month of their first day in office.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Upon the creation of a new Executive Branch position the President must notify the Senate President through an executive order within seven (7) business days.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The Executive Cabinet
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The Executive Cabinet shall advise the President and Vice-President on matters pertaining to the coordination of the Executive Branch responsibilities.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Executive Staff
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Executive Staff is appointed by the President and is not subject to confirmation by the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;The Executive Staff derives its authority from the President and has no power or authority unless granted by the President or Vice-President.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Presidental Appointment and Dismissal
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Candidate Search
    				&lt;ol&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;No position requiring a Senate confirmation may be filled with out effective advertisement via University email.&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;The advertisements must be visible for a reasonable amount of time at the SGA desk or the SGA office.&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;The President shall be responsible for the advertising of all positions open for candidate search.&lt;/li&gt;
    				&lt;/ol&gt;
    			&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Appointment to Executive Branch Positions
    				&lt;ol&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;The President shall appoint all non-elected member(s) of the Executive Branch.&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;All appointed positions to the level of Executive Cabinet Position shall require confirmation by a simple majority vote of the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
    					&lt;li&gt;Any individual appointed to a Cabinet level position may serve in an interim capacity until a time in which they can be confirmed at a regularly scheduled Senate meeting.
    						&lt;ol&gt;
    							&lt;li&gt;No individual may serve in an interim position for longer than thirty (30) days.&lt;/li&gt;
    						&lt;/ol&gt;
    					&lt;/li&gt;
    				&lt;/ol&gt;
    			&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Executive Branch Vacancies&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Student Body President
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Should the Student Body President announce to the Senate President, via Executive Memo (email), a period of absence the Vice-President shall assume the duties of Student Body President until the Student Body President resumes their duties.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Should the Vice-President not be available the next in the line of continuity shall take the place of the Vice-President as the acting Student Body President until conditions in 300.9.1.1 are met.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Student Body Vice-President
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Should the Student Body Vice-President announce to the Senate President and the Student Body President, via memo (email), a period of absence the Chief-Of-Staff shall assume the duties of Student Body Vice-President until the Student Body Vice-President resumes their duties.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Treasurer
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Should the Treasurer announce to the Senate President and the Student Body President, via memo (email), a period of absence the Chief-Of-Staff shall assume the duties of Treasurer until the Treasurer resumes their duties.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;All other Executive Vacancies
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;All other Executive Vacancies shall be filled in accordance with the Executive Handbook.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Continuity&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;Should the office of Student Body President become vacant, the following continuity plan shall be enacted.
    		&lt;ol&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Student Body Vice-President shall assume the office of Student Body President.&lt;/li&gt;
    			&lt;li&gt;Should the Student Body Vice-President not be able to assume the office of the Student Body President, then the Senate President shall assume the office of the Student Body President.&lt;/li&gt;
    		&lt;/ol&gt;
    	&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;For any other elected vacancy other than Student Body President shall be filled by the runner-up for that position pending approval of the Senate stated in Article III of the SGA Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Powers of the President-Elect&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The President-Elect shall have the ability to designate all incoming cabinet level positions and Executive staff.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The President-Elect shall have the ability to dismiss any designee&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Transition Period&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The Executive transition period shall begin the day after the President-Elect is officially announced and conclude when the President-Elect takes office.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;During the transition period the President-Elect must meet with the outgoing President to discuss turnover a minimum of four (4) times, unless extreme circumstances prohibit from completing this requirement. Extreme circumstances are defined by the Student Body President.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The outgoing administration shall provide the President-Elect with all available documents pertaining to the Executive Branch.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;External Representation&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The President shall act as the Student Government Association main representative for all external communication, including but not limited to; Student Body Representation to the State and Federal Legislature, Florida Student Association, and any other governmental bodies.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
    &lt;h3&gt;Internal Representation and Communication&lt;/h3&gt;
    &lt;ol&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;The Executive Branch shall serve as the representation and communication of SGA to University Administration. Including but not limited to; Office of the President, Office of the Provost, Board of Trustees, and the University Departments.&lt;/li&gt;
    	&lt;li&gt;After initial contact, relevant bodies within SGA may maintain communication with University Administration.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Statutes" /><summary type="html">Last Revised: 4-3-19 Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Title IV - The Legislative Branch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleIV/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title IV - The Legislative Branch" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Statutes/title_iv</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleIV/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Last Revised: 4-3-19&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-4-the-legislative-branch&quot;&gt;Title 4 The Legislative Branch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 400: Legislative Authority&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 401: General Requirements&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 402: Ranking Officers of the Senate&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 403: Order of Succession&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 404: Legislation of the Legislative Branch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 405: Composition of Legislation&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
	#legal-list { 
		counter-reset: section; 
		counter-increment: section -1;
	}
	#legal-list h3:before { 
		content: &quot;40&quot; counter(section) &quot;. &quot;;
		counter-increment: section;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
	#legal-list ol {
		counter-reset: clause;
		list-style: none outside none;
		text-indent: -1em;
	}
	#legal-list ol li { counter-increment: clause; }
	#legal-list ol li:before {
		content: &quot;40&quot; counter(section) &quot;.&quot; counters(clause, &quot;.&quot;) &quot;. &quot;;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;html&gt;
&lt;body id=&quot;legal-list&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Legislative Authority&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The composition and authority of the Legislative Branch shall be as contained in the SGA Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;General Requirements&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Senators shall be in compliance with the standards for being a member of the Legislative Branch as stated in the SGA Constitution and SGA Statutes.
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;All Senators are required to serve on at least one Standing Committee.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Standing Committees of the Senate and voting rights of members of Standing Committees shall be outlined in the Senate Handbook.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Senators are expected to attend all Senate Meetings and Standing Committee Meetings for which they are voting Members.
					&lt;ol&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Attendance at these meetings shall be monitored by means of the Legislative Accountability Report which is further outlined within the Senate Handbook&lt;/li&gt;
						&lt;li&gt;Additional and alternative attendance requirements may be outlined in the Student Government Senate Handbook&lt;/li&gt;
					&lt;/ol&gt;
				&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Ranking Officers of the Senate&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The following are ranking officers of the Senate:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Senate President&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Senate President Pro Tempore&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Senate Audit and Budget Committee Chair&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Senate Information and Communication Committee Chair&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Senate Student Organization Committee Chair&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Ranking officers will take on their position at the beginning of the session and will terminate their position at the end of the session.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Duties of the Senate President:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Those duties enumerated in the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;To represent the Senate before the administration.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;To prepare the agenda for all Senate General Meetings&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;To oversee the day-to-day operations of the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Those duties enumerated in the Senate Handbook&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Sign all necessary legislation approved by the Senate and notify the relevant parties&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Dutios of the Senate Pro Tempore:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;To fulfill the duties of the Senate President should they become unable to perform their duties.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;To aid the Senate President in his or her duties.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Those dutios enumerated in the Senate Handbook&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Duties of the Committee Chairs
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;To manage all activities within their respective Committees.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;To maintain attendance records within their respective Committees.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Those duties outlined for Committee Chairs in the Senate Handbook.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Order of Succession&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Should the Senate President be unable to fulfill their duties; the order of succession shall be:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Senate President Pro Tempore&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Audit and Budget Committee chair&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Student Organization Committee chair&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Information and Communication Committee Chair&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Legislation of the Legislative Branch&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Legislation approved by the Legislative Branch must be approved or vetoed by the Student Body President within fifteen (15) business days of approval. The legislation will pass by default if the President fails to act.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Legislation will follow the classifications outlined in Article 3, Section 6, part h of the SGA Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Senate President shall submit all bills to the Student Body President within five (5) business days of the bill being passed by the Senate.
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;If the Senate President does not submit the bills within five (5) business days, the Senate President Pro Tempore will submit the bills within another five (5) business days.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;All vetoed bills that have been overridden by a Supermajority vote of the Senate will follow the above procedures outlined in 404.3.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Composition of Legislation&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;All forms of Legislation except for subsidiary budgets will contain the following:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Title and Subject&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Legislative Intent&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Enacting Clause&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Effective Date&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Senate Sponsor&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Title and Subject
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The subject of each bill will be briefly expressed in its title and subject.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Legislative Intent
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Legislative intent explains the purpose and intent of the legislation.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Enacting Clause
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Enacting clauses state the entity that has the authority to enact the legislation.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Effective Date
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Effective Date states when the legislation will take effect.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Senate Sponsor
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The senate sponsor is the senator who initially promotes the legislation.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Statutes" /><summary type="html">Last Revised: 4-3-19 Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Title V - The Judicial Branch</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleV/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Title V - The Judicial Branch" /><published>2019-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2019-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/Statutes/title_v</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Statutes/TitleV/">&lt;blockquote&gt;
  &lt;p&gt;Last Revised: 4-3-19&lt;/p&gt;

  &lt;p&gt;Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;title-5-the-judicial-branch&quot;&gt;Title 5 The Judicial Branch&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 500: Judicial Composition and Authority&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 501: Judicial Rules of Procedure&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 502: Ranking Officers of the Judicial Branch&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 503: Rights of an individual Before the Court&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 504: Temporary Justices&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Chapter 505: Judicial Meetings&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;style&gt;
	#legal-list { 
		counter-reset: section; 
		counter-increment: section -1;
	}
	#legal-list h3:before { 
		content: &quot;50&quot; counter(section) &quot;. &quot;;
		counter-increment: section;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
	#legal-list ol {
		counter-reset: clause;
		list-style: none outside none;
		text-indent: -1em;
	}
	#legal-list ol li { counter-increment: clause; }
	#legal-list ol li:before {
		content: &quot;50&quot; counter(section) &quot;.&quot; counters(clause, &quot;.&quot;) &quot;. &quot;;
		margin: 0 0.5em 0 0;
	}
&lt;/style&gt;

&lt;html&gt;
&lt;body id=&quot;legal-list&quot;&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Judicial Composition and Authority&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The composition and authority of the Judicial Branch shall be as contained in the SGA Constitution under Article 5, Section 3, Parts A, B, and C.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Judicial Rules of Procedure&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Judicial Branch Trial Procedures will govern the procedures for trials within the Judicial Branch.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Ranking Officers of the Judicial Branch&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The following are ranking officers of the Judicial Branch
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Chief Justice&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Senior Justice&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Duties of the Chief Justice:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Call and Reside over all meetings&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Supervise the administration of the Judicial Branch&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Keep all records of the Judicial Branch necessary to follow Public Record Retention Laws.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Maintain an understanding of major events occurring in SGA&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Complete additional tasks as outlined in SGA Constitution&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Appoint a Judicial Clerk and Judicial Marshal as needed.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Duties of the Senior Justice:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;All the responsibilities of an Associate Justice&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Act as the Chief Justice when they are absent&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;These roles will be further described in the Judicial Handbook/ROP&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Rights of Individuals before the Court&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Supreme Court will create a file for each case heard.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Individuals appearing before the Supreme Court will be guaranteed the following:
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The right to due process.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The right to an expedient trial.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The right to be aware of Supreme Court Procedures.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The right to be heard by quorum.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The right to be heard without ridicule, interference, or unnecessary interruption.&lt;/li&gt; 
				&lt;li&gt;The right to ask any Justice any questions concerning any procedural matter or concerning rights and privileges of the individual before the Supreme Court.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The right to be free from slanderous remarks or unwarranted accusations during any Supreme Court proceedings.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The right to representation of counsel by a fellow student of their choosing, or the right to self-representation.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;All parties in a trial must notify the Supreme Court who will be representing them at least twenty-four (24) hours before a trial.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Temporary Justices&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Chief Justice may appoint Temporary Justices
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The Chief Justice shall assign an Associate Justice this duty if the Chief Justice is subject to recusal.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Temporary Justice qualifications
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Temporary Justices can be appointed if there is a recusal or less than seven (7) current members of the Supreme Court.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Temporary justices must meet the eligibility requirements stated in Article V. Section 3. part C. of the SGA Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;A Temporary Justice is on the Supreme Court until
			&lt;ol&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;The individual is nominated by the President and confirmed by the Senate to be a Supreme Court Justice.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;An individual is nominated by the President and confirmed by the Senate to the Supreme Court replacing the Temporary Justice.&lt;/li&gt;
				&lt;li&gt;Their membership is no longer needed by the Supreme Court.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;/ol&gt;
		&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;h3&gt;Judicial Meetings&lt;/h3&gt;
	&lt;ol&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Chief Justice will preside over meetings&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Chief Justice will determine the time, day and place of the Judicial Branch meetings&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Meetings will consist of all members of the Judicial Branch&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;Quorum for all meetings will be met with a simple majority.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;li&gt;The Judicial Branch may define specific types of meetings in their Rules of Procedure.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;/body&gt;
&lt;/html&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Statutes" /><summary type="html">Last Revised: 4-3-19 Originally Written by: Session 4 LEB</summary></entry></feed>