<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2021-12-19T14:49:03-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Florida Poly Student Government</title><subtitle>Welcome to the Florida Poly Student Government page!  Here you can find all of our official documents  including statutes, meeting minutes, and more!</subtitle><entry><title type="html">SGA Constitution</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/AboutConstitution/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SGA Constitution" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/about_constitution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/AboutConstitution/">&lt;p&gt;The Florida Polytechnic University Student Constitution, enacted in February 2015, is a dynamic document that establishes the Student Government Association, its mission, powers, and duties. With the signing of the Constitution, the SGA is formally operated by the students and for the students, a highly visible testament to democracy at the university level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;statutes&quot;&gt;Statutes&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title I - Introduction to SGA Statutes&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title II - Officer Procedures&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title III - The Executive Branch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title IV - The Legislative Branch&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Title V - The Judicial Branch&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="AboutSGA" /><summary type="html">The Florida Polytechnic University Student Constitution, enacted in February 2015, is a dynamic document that establishes the Student Government Association, its mission, powers, and duties. With the signing of the Constitution, the SGA is formally operated by the students and for the students, a highly visible testament to democracy at the university level.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">SGA Branches</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Branches/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="SGA Branches" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/branches</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Branches/">&lt;p&gt;The Student Government Association is composed of an Executive, Legislative, and Judicial branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;executive-branch&quot;&gt;Executive Branch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Executive Branch includes the Student Body President, Vice President, Treasurer, Secretary, and an Executive Cabinet. The Cabinet includes various Executive Committees as appointed by the Student Body President. They are the students’ voice and liaison between the students and the administration.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sgavicepresident@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Contact the Executive Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;legislative-branch&quot;&gt;Legislative Branch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Legislative Branch is comprised of senators represented by class years, degree programs, and on- and off-campus students. The Senate enacts statutes, allocates funds and oversees campus organizations. The Legislative Branch will grow as the University grows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;/LegislativeCommittees/&quot;&gt;View All Committees&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;judicial-branch&quot;&gt;Judicial Branch&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Judicial Branch is the Supreme Court, comprised of a Chief Justice and six Associate Justices. The seven Justices are appointed by the Student Body President and confirmed by the Senate. The Supreme Court hears student concerns, helps conduct all SGA elections and holds trials for officials who breach the SGA Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;mailto:sgajudicial@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Contact the Judicial Branch&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="AboutSGA" /><summary type="html">The Student Government Association is composed of an Executive, Legislative, and Judicial branch.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">The Constitution of the Student Body of Florida Polytechnic University</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/Constitution/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="The Constitution of the Student Body of Florida Polytechnic University" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/constitution</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/Constitution/">&lt;div style=&quot;text-align: center&quot;&gt;&lt;img src=&quot;/assets/ConstitutionHeader.png&quot; /&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;the-constitution-of-the-student-body-of-florida-polytechnic-university&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;The Constitution of the Student Body of Florida Polytechnic University&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h2&gt;

&lt;center&gt;Adopted by the Florida Polytechnic University Student Body on &lt;i&gt;February 4th of 2015&lt;/i&gt;.&lt;/center&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
We, the Student Body of the Florida Polytechnic University:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Represent and defend the rights and interests of our students to the University, local community, and government&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide a forum for the expressions of student views and interests&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Promote the academic freedom and responsibility and high standards of education&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Provide services and organize events for the benefit of students&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Recognize and understand our responsibilities to the University, local community, and humanity&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Do hereby establish this Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-i-declaration-of-rights-and-responsibilities&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article I: DECLARATION OF RIGHTS AND RESPONSIBILITIES&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-political-power&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Political power.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All political power granted by authorities authorized under the Constitution of the State of Florida, laws, and regulations of the State of Florida is inherent in the Student Body.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-basic-rights&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Basic rights.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Every student is guaranteed certain rights under the constitutions and laws of the United States and State of Florida. Student government recognizes these rights.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Additionally students are guaranteed:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The right to vote in student government elections.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The right to submit initiatives and referendums for ratification by the electorate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The right to recall and remove elected officials from office, through process Stated in &lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article VII, Section 1.&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The right to address student government officials at regularly scheduled times and places.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-honor-code&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Honor Code.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All Students are bound by the Honor Code and shall be held accountable to it. The Honor Code states:&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;“We, the members of the Florida Polytechnic University community, pledge to hold ourselves and our peers to the highest standards of honesty and integrity.”&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-discrimination-prohibited&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4. Discrimination Prohibited.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Government Association (SGA) and any organization that receives SGA funding shall not discriminate on the basis of race, creed, color, religion, age, disability, sex, sexual orientation, gender identity and expression, marital status, national origin, political opinions or affiliations, veteran status, legal status, or any other classification as provided by law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-ii-general-provisions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article II: GENERAL PROVISIONS&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-student-body&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Student Body.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body shall be held to SGA laws put forth, as well as entitled to all privileges and immunities of students provided for, in this: “The Constitution of the Student Body of Florida Polytechnic University”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-student-government&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Student government.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All student Government officials shall be full-time students.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-student-government-officials&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Student Government Officials.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Government shall be divided into a Legislative, an Executive, and a Judicial branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-branches-of-government&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4. Branches of government.&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Student Government shall be divided into a Legislative, an Executive, and a Judicial branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. Exercise of Powers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;No person belonging to one (1) branch shall exercise any powers appertaining to either of the other branches unless expressly provided by the Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. Exclusionary of Powers.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;The Senate may provide by Code of Conduct for Student Government offices considered exclusionary, but the following positions shall always be exclusionary: Student Body President, Student Body Vice President, Student Body Treasurer, Student Body Chief of Staff, Supervisor of Elections (or election committee), Heads of Cabinet or Agency Heads, and Cabinet Directors for the Executive Branch.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C. Offices Explicitly Non-exclusionary.&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;Nothing in this Constitution shall be construed to prohibit any student from holding an exclusionary office and simultaneously holding as a member of the Constitution Revision Commission, a member of an independent body having only advisory powers created by Student Body Statutes, or a member of a committee or commission created by the Student Body President.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-iii-the-legislature&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article III: THE LEGISLATURE&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-legislative-authority&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Legislative Authority&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The legislative authority of the Student Body shall be vested in the Student Senate herein after referred to as “The Senate”.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-composition&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Composition&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. Division of Representation&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;PADDING-LEFT: 75px&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Senate will be composed of representatives from each of the Colleges of the University. Graduate and Undecided/Non-Degree Seeking Students shall each be considered a separate college for the purpose of composing the Senate. Seats will also be allocated for the Freshman, Sophomore, Junior, and Senior class along with a seat for on-campus and off-campus students. The total number of Senate seats will be ten (10) plus one (1) seat for every 240 students with a maximum number of thirty (30) senators. Every College will have at least one (1) representative. The apportionment of the seats will be set according to the percentages of the total number of students enrolled at each of the respective Colleges as outlined within the Constitution or Statutes.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;If passed, this amendment will go into effect for the 2020 spring general election.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. Structure of Senate&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;margin-left:5%&quot;&gt;There shall be a:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul style=&quot;PADDING-LEFT: 75px&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Senate President, elected by The Senate to be the Speaker of the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Senate President Pro Tempore, nominated by the Senate President and approved by The Senate to act as speaker in absence of the President.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A number of officers elected or appointed as stated in the Senate Rules and Procedures as written and designed by The Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-senate-session&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Senate Session&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The previous Senate will be dissolved once the President of the new Senate is confirmed at the first official Senate meeting after the Fall semester election, in which both the previous Senate and the new Senate are present. At such time, the new Senate session will begin.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-election-of-the-senate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4. Election of the Senate&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate shall be elected by majority vote for the Senator candidate of each division.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-5-vacancy-in-the-senate&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 5. Vacancy in The Senate&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Upon vacancy in The Senate, the Election Committee will appoint the next highest voted candidate from the previous election to office and The Senate will approve them by a majority vote. A successor shall serve for the remainder of the term.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Should a Representative position go unfilled and is also unable to be filled by previously stated vacancy procedures, the Representative position will remain empty. In tandem with the Fall General Election, a vote for the unfilled Representative position will be initiated in conjunction with the elections for the Freshman Senator position to serve the remainder of the term.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-6-procedures&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 6. Procedures&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;No bill shall become law unless a Senator introduces the bill, the bill is read, and (during a subsequent meeting) the bill passes by vote of the Senate. Reference Article III, Section 7, Part a for vote requirements.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;No bill shall become law without the signature of the Student Body President, except when the Student Body President has not vetoed the bill within seven (7) days after presentment, in which case the bill shall become law.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The University President or the University President’s designee may veto a proposed law. The Student Body President must notify the Senate President in writing no later than ten (10) days after receiving the veto stating the reasons for the University President’s veto.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Student Body Treasurer shall have veto equal with that of the Student Body President in all matters concerning Budget approval and revisions to said budget. The Student Body Treasurer shall have exclusive veto in matters concerning appropriations from Special Request Funds.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Any Bill which the Student Body President and Treasurer choose to veto, shall be considered as having been vetoed once.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;A vetoed bill may be enacted notwithstanding the veto of the Student Body President or Treasurer if it is read a third time in full and passed by a super majority vote of the members of The Senate present and voting at a regular meeting after receiving the document of the written reason of why the Student Body President or Treasurer enacted the veto.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Quorum necessary to conduct business shall be one-third (1/3) of the total Senate membership. For further clarifications, see The Senate Handbook.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Legislation of The Senate shall only be classified as:
		&lt;ol type=&quot;1&quot;&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Bill of Law&lt;/b&gt; – Subject to Veto.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Budget&lt;/b&gt; – Primary or subsidiary budgets, of which all budgets shall be considered bills of law and subject to veto as described in this section.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Special Request Authorization&lt;/b&gt; – An appropriation from special request funds requiring a super majority vote for enactment subject to veto as described in this section.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Directive&lt;/b&gt; – An order requiring a majority vote for enactment that advises, orders, or prescribes the method for an SGA Member to fulfill a duty provided for in the Constitution and is not subject to veto.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Order to Action&lt;/b&gt; – A directive requiring a super majority vote which mandates that any SGA Affiliate to act on any action that SGA has previously assigned them.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Resolution&lt;/b&gt; – An expression of the sentiment of The Senate requiring a super majority vote for passage and not subject to veto.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;&lt;b&gt;Immediate Action Clause&lt;/b&gt; – The Senate will have the authority to pass any legislation in the same Official Meeting in which it is presented. This subsection expires midnight on March 4th 2015, at which time this clause becomes unusable and unextendable for further use. The power of the Senate to pass legislature is returned to the power specified in &lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article III, Section 6, Part a&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt;.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Senate shall also exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-7-powers-duties-and-limitations&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 7. Powers, Duties, and Limitations&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enact, Constitutional bylaws to be known as Student Body Statutes by majority vote, with the exception of bylaws concerning elections, which shall require a super majority vote of the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Express the will and/or sentiments of The Senate in Resolution form.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Propose and act on Constitutional Amendments.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Provide for the compilation and publication of legislation.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Advise and consent, by an applicable vote, any and all appointments made by the Student Body President and Executive Branch.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Impeach Student Body officers, both elected and appointed, according to procedures described in Article VII.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Approve and allocate the fiscal budget of the Student Government Association, as provided by the Activity Fee.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Allocate all student funds, as provided by the Activity Fee.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Establish its own meeting times and operate under Roberts Rules of Parliamentary Procedure.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Establish means through which the Student Body can actively participate in the formulation of policies affecting the students of the Florida Polytechnic University.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Override a veto by the Student Body President by a super majority vote of the Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Request a review of a veto of the Student Body President by a Student Affairs designated official by a majority vote of The Senate. This is asking the official advice and clarification on the veto of the Student Body President.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Override a second veto by the Student Body President with super majority vote and refer the legislation to the University President for ultimate review and decision. The President of the University shall have twenty-one (21) days from the time the Office of the University President receives the legislation to veto or sign measures passed by The Senate. If the University President fails to reply within the timeframe, the law shall not pass.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Issue subpoenas by a majority vote of The Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Assemble in open meetings at least twice a month, for the deliberation of legislation and the business of the Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Call for a referendum of the Student Body through a super majority vote on a resolution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Create and appoint committees, or commissions, not provided in this Constitution, if deemed necessary, provided that these bodies do not contravene with the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enforce specified and pre-stated standards for clubs, organizations, and committees to maintain their SGA sponsorship and funding. This will be specified in The Senate Handbook.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-8-prohibitions&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 8. Prohibitions&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Senate shall not:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enact any law that abridges its powers delegated by the constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appropriate funds for a period of more than one (1) year.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Infringe the secrecy of the ballot in any Student Body election.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Deny scheduled speaking privileges or recognized speaking privileges in an official Senate meeting to the Student Body, SGA Affiliates, and Faculty until recognized.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Deny unscheduled speaking privileges to Executive Director of the Honor Code Administration, any University Administrative Officer, College Dean, Student Body Chief of Staff, or Chief Justice Meet in a closed session.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Change the dates of Student Body elections in the six (6) weeks before the scheduled election.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Change the election laws during the three (3) weeks before the scheduled election to be effective for that election.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Enact any law embracing more than one (1) subject and matter properly connected to that subject.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-iv-executive-branch&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article IV: Executive Branch&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-executive-power&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Executive Power&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All executive powers of the Student Body shall be vested in a Student Body President, Student Body Vice President, Student Body Treasurer, and Student Body Chief of Staff, who will be known as the SGA Executive Board.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-election&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Election&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The SGA Executive Board, shall be chosen in the spring general election by a majority of the Student Body voting in the election, and shall serve for one-year (1) terms as provided for by the Constitution.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-vacancy-in-executive-offices&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Vacancy in Executive Offices&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Upon vacancy in the office of Student Body President, the Student Body Vice President shall fill the position. A vacancy in any executive position other than the President will be filled by the runner up of the election previous, pending approval of the Senate as stated in &lt;b&gt;&lt;em&gt;Article III, Section 5, Part r&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/b&gt; who shall serve for the remainder of the term.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-4-powers-of-the-student-body-president&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 4. Powers of the Student Body President&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body President shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the chief executive officer of the Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Take care that Code of Conduct is faithfully executed.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Have the power to veto legislation as provided for by the Constitution as seen in Article III, Section 6, Part b.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Present to The Senate, each term of the University, a State of the Campus message.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Create and appoint committees, or commissions, not provided in this Constitution, if deemed necessary, provided that these bodies do not contravene with the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Convene special meetings of The Senate, if deemed necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary. The Student Body President also has the authority to approve or reject the appointments made by the other members of the SGA Executive Board.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint a Student Honor Code Executive Director to be a member of the Cabinet.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the Student Body’s official representative to the University’s Board of Trustees and the Florida Student Association.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-5-executive-departments&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 5. Executive Departments&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Executive departments may be established by The Senate, with the Head of each department to be appointed by the Student Body President and confirmed with at least a concurrence of a majority of The Senate. Officers of the executive departments shall be responsible to the Student Body President for the execution of their duties and shall be subject to removal by the Student Body President. The terms of the Heads of the executive departments shall expire concurrently with the expiration of the regular terms of the elected executive officials. The Heads of the executive departments may appoint subordinate aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-6-cabinet&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 6. Cabinet&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There shall be a Cabinet, consisting of the heads of the executive departments and other Student Government officials that The Senate shall provide by law to be Cabinet-Level.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-7-powers-of-the-student-body-vice-president&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 7. Powers of the Student Body Vice President&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body Vice President shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the Chief Services Officer of the Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Assist the Student Body President in the conduct of government.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise the powers and duties of the Student Body President in their absence.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt; Attend meetings of all service committees and entities under Student Government to stay in communication with these departments and organizations. If the Vice President cannot personally attend, the Vice President shall appoint an aide to go in their stead.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-8-powers-of-the-student-body-treasurer&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 8. Powers of the Student Body Treasurer&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body Treasurer shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the Chief Financial Officer of the Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Keep complete and accurate accounts of all Student Body funds on deposit with the University Comptroller.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Have the power to veto legislation as provided for by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Sign all requisitions on Student Body funds on order of The Senate.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Assist the Student Body President and Student Body Vice President in the conduct of government.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Attend all official meetings of the Audit and Budget Committee as a non-voting member.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-9-powers-of-the-student-chief-of-staff&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 9. Powers of the Student Chief of Staff&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Body Secretary shall:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Act as the Chief Organizational Officer of the Student Body&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Record SGA Executive Board and official Senate meeting minutes or appoint an aide to do so in their stead.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Post minutes of the SGA meeting in a public forum.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Email minutes of SGA Executive Board and official Senate meetings to members.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Send reminders regarding meetings and events out to the SGA Executive Board and Senate members.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Take attendance at All SGA Executive Board and official Senate meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Assist the SGA Executive Board in the conduct of government.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Appoint aides or other officials not provided for by the Constitution, if deemed necessary.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Communicate regularly with Senate leadership through appropriate methods such as attending Senate leadership meetings.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Exercise all other powers and duties provided by the Constitution.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h3 id=&quot;article-v-judicial-branch&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;center&gt;&lt;u&gt;Article V: Judicial Branch&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/center&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h3&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-1-judicial-powers&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 1. Judicial Powers&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All judicial power of the Student Body shall be vested in the Judicial Branch, and such other tribunals as are established by law.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-2-administration&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 2. Administration&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Practice and procedure:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Chief Justice of the Supreme Court shall be the chief administrative officer of the judicial system.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;The Judicial Branch shall adopt its own internal rules of practice and procedure for itself.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;section-3-judicial-board&quot;&gt;&lt;strong&gt;&lt;u&gt;Section 3. Judicial Board&lt;/u&gt;&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;A. Organization&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Judicial Board shall consist of the Chief Justice and up to six justices. The Chief Justice shall preside over the Judicial Board. Simple majority of members shall constitute a quorum. The concurrence in judgment of a simple majority members shall be necessary for a decision. The Judicial Board shall provide in its rules of practice and procedure the process for assigning qualified students to temporary duty as substitutes, where recusals for cause would prohibit the Judicial Board from convening because of the requirements of this section. To be eligible to be assigned to temporary duty, a person must meet the minimal qualifications of membership on the Judicial Board. The Chief Justice shall be responsible for selecting temporary Justices and shall assign an Associate Justice this duty if the Chief Justice is subject to recusal.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;B. Jurisdiction&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ol type=&quot;a&quot;&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Shall interpret any provision of the Constitution or any law that is written within:
		&lt;ol type=&quot;i&quot;&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Upon any written petition of five percent (5%) of the total Student Body.&lt;/li&gt;
			&lt;li&gt;Request of the Student Body President.&lt;/li&gt;
		&lt;/ol&gt;
	&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Shall, upon written petition of any member of the Student Body, and for good and fair cause shown as determined by the Chief Justice and to be consistent with the internal procedures of the supreme court, order any SGA Affiliate or any person who has attended an SGA sponsored event or activity, to appear in front of the court. This shall only occur if the student performs any act that violates this Constitution, any applicable Code of Conduct, State, or Federal Law.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Shall hear appeals from tribunals and lower courts as established by the Supreme Court.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;May issue any writ necessary to the complete exercise of its jurisdiction.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Will suspend and terminate the position of any SGA Officer convicted of a Felony in an official State or Federal Court during their term in office.&lt;/li&gt;
	&lt;li&gt;Shall maintain a permanent election result file of every student body election.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;C. Subpoena Power&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Supreme Court shall have the power to issue subpoenas and subpoena duces tecum directed at any SGA Affiliate, returnable before the Supreme Court or any tribunal it designates.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;D. Eligibility and Tenure&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;No person shall be eligible to hold the office of Chief Justice or Associate Justice of the Supreme Court unless that person has successfully completed first year writing requirements, and attained a total cumulative 2.50 grade point average. The Chief Justice and Associate Justices of the Supreme Court shall have the right to remain in office without reappointment until they are awarded a degree.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;E. Vacancy in Office&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Whenever a vacancy occurs in the office of the Chief Justice or Associate Justice of the Judicial Branch, the Student Body President shall fill the vacancy by appointment, subject to a super majority confirmation vote by The Senate.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;F. Clerk and Marshal&lt;/strong&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The Chief Justice may appoint a clerk and a marshal for the Supreme Court who shall hold office during the pleasure of the Chief Justice and perform such duties pertinent for to the court as the Chief Justice directs.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="Constitution" /><summary type="html"></summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Legislative Committees</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/LegislativeCommittees/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Legislative Committees" /><published>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</published><updated>2021-12-19T00:00:00-05:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/legislative_committees</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/LegislativeCommittees/">&lt;p&gt;Florida Poly’s Student Government Association currently has four legistaltive committees.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;audit-and-budget-committee&quot;&gt;Audit and Budget Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Audit and Budget Committee (ABC) deals with Student Government’s funding. A major role of the ABC is to help Registered Student Organizations (RSO) receive funding by submitting a budget proposal and going through revisions which will then be passed on to Senate to see if there are any more revisions needed. The ABC is committed to helping students and RSOs receive funding through certain line items in the SGA Budget.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ABC@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Audit and Budget Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;information-and-communications-committee&quot;&gt;Information and Communications Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Information and Communications Committee (ICC) deals with SGA and Legislative Branch communication. A major role of the ICC is to help keep students and other SGA members informed. The ICC is committed to keeping SGA and students informed throughout the year.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:ICC@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Information and Communication Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;legislative-executive-board&quot;&gt;Legislative Executive Board&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They do be doin stuff&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:senate@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Legislative Executive Board&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h2 id=&quot;student-organizations-committee&quot;&gt;Student Organizations Committee&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The Student Organizations Committee (SOC) deals with student organizations and clubs. A major role of the SOC is to approve and manage Registered Student Organizations. Students may submit paperwork to apply for a new organization at any time, and the SOC will work with the students through the process. The SOC is here for the students and to help create a better, more active campus life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Contact the &lt;a href=&quot;mailto:SOC@floridapoly.edu&quot;&gt;Student Organizations Committee&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="AboutSGA" /><summary type="html">Florida Poly’s Student Government Association currently has four legistaltive committees.</summary></entry></feed>